<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>KAKAN</title><link>https://kakan.omg.lol/</link><description>Recent content on KAKAN</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</managingEditor><webMaster>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</webMaster><copyright>Copyright © 2022 KAKAN. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 14:09:08 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kakan.omg.lol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Experience with Jellyfin</title><link>https://kakan.omg.lol/posts/jellyfin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 14:09:08 +0530</pubDate><author>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</author><guid>https://kakan.omg.lol/posts/jellyfin/</guid><description>Before we go further, I&amp;rsquo;d first like to say that I absolutely love using Jellyfin and I&amp;rsquo;ll continue using it after this, too.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the advantages!
Advantages: 1. Media metadata This is basically the reason why people would want Jellyfin over say, a file manager. It manages to grab most of my media automatically from different sites, and it&amp;rsquo;s really accurate at it too!
And if that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, it also fetches actor information, networks etc and lets you browse according to that, too.</description><content>&lt;p>Before we go further, I&amp;rsquo;d first like to say that I absolutely love using &lt;a href="https://jellyfin.org/">Jellyfin&lt;/a>
and I&amp;rsquo;ll continue using it after this, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the advantages!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="advantages">Advantages:&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="1-media-metadata">1. Media metadata&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is basically the reason why people would want Jellyfin over say, a file
manager. It manages to grab most of my media automatically from different
sites, and it&amp;rsquo;s really accurate at it too!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, it also fetches actor information, networks etc and
lets you browse according to that, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-playback-historystatistics">2. Playback History/Statistics&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Another reason I like it is because of &lt;a href="https://github.com/jellyfin/jellyfin-plugin-playbackreporting/">Playback reporting&lt;/a>
which offers a nice view of how much I&amp;rsquo;ve watched, or how many. I love seeing
data and this is really nice since it&amp;rsquo;s a centralised place for all my users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-sync-with-other-services">3. Sync with other services&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Jellyfin has plugins to sync watch lists and library with services like &lt;a href="https://github.com/jellyfin/jellyfin-plugin-trakt">Trakt.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is really nice, especially if you want to know if you already have
something in your library, or if you need to download/rip it from somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It also has your watch history, and Trakt itself provides a lot of statistics
which adds to its feature set, in my opinion.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-plugins">4. Plugins&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By default, only point 1 is possible OOTB. However, with the help of its plugin
ecosystem, you can add various things to it, like the above mentioned features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is something all of the competition has, but I still felt like I should
atleast mention it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="5-multiple-users">5. Multiple Users&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is also something that sets Jellyfin apart from &amp;ldquo;local&amp;rdquo; media managers
which let you store, view and update metadata and keep a playback history,
but tie it to a single user. Often times, its annoying and also cannot be
changed since its usually stored in NFO files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, that reminds me, Jellyfin has an option to store metadata in NFO files
at the location, which I always keep turned off because I like them
directories kept clean! :yum:&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="disadvantages">Disadvantages:&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Time to move on to the not-so-good parts in my experience of self hosting Jellyfin&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-mixed-libraries-dont-work-well">1. Mixed Libraries don&amp;rsquo;t work well&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a surprise to anybody, but if you have a lot of mixed content
i.e, TV shows and movies in one folder (&lt;em>say you have one folder for all Anime&lt;/em>),
then you should consider moving them to different folders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem arises since Jellyfin can no longer safely say &amp;ldquo;this is a movie&amp;rdquo;,
or that &amp;ldquo;this is a series&amp;rdquo;, so in the end you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with multiple movies
marked as series and vice versa. It&amp;rsquo;s mildly annoying at best, and unfixable
at worst.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>My solution&lt;/strong>: I moved Anime movies into my main Movies library, and then created
a collection of all the anime movies. That way, I can still browse them separately.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-lack-of-plugins">2. Lack of Plugins&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is mostly because Jellyfin is changing from Emby, so plugins made for Emby
might not work anymore. And because Jellyfin itself is getting updated, older
and unmaintained plugins might not work anymore either. While there are some
really good plugins that do work, it&amp;rsquo;d be nice if there were even more maintained
ones available to use&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortuneately, this is kind of a chicken egg problem and I&amp;rsquo;ve no idea how this
might get solved. That said, there are some really good plugins out there, I even
&lt;a href="https://github.com/stars/theKAKAN/lists/jellyfin-plugins">made a list of ones I found interesting&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-metadata-searchupdate-is-slow">3. Metadata Search/Update is&amp;hellip; slow&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why this happens, but if you have multiple metadata providers,
you&amp;rsquo;ll likely experience major slowdowns if you enter broad enough terms for
searching.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and sometimes the images don&amp;rsquo;t get updated. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a cache issue, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>My solution&lt;/strong>: I grab the IMDb ID and search via that, in case the builtin
metadata downloader gets/grabs the wrong metadata&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-tv-shows-are-kind-of-a-mess">4. TV Shows are kind of a mess&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Honestly, this is more of a standard/naming problem than it is with Jellyfin,
but nonetheless, it&amp;rsquo;s a problem that I experienced a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, many series are listed differently under different providers.&lt;br>
For example:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Kitsu has 6 different entries for &amp;ldquo;My Hero Academia&amp;rdquo;, for each of its different seasons.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Trakt has one entry for &amp;ldquo;My Hero Academia&amp;rdquo;, with 6 seasons inside it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This same pattern continues for many different series — as well as some movies —
which makes it annoying to efficiently categorise and manage a library.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I hope this post helped you in some way. To me, Jellyfin is not just a media
server, it&amp;rsquo;s also a playground for me to play with my collection of movies
as well as find ways to efficiently organise them for future usage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I simply chose Jellyfin as its the FOSS option, which makes it likely that
in the odd case that it gets abandoned, I might be able to keep tweaking it
to make sure that it &lt;em>just works™&lt;/em> and suits my needs.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://kakan.omg.lol/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 19:36:06 +0530</pubDate><author>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</author><guid>https://kakan.omg.lol/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>Hello world! This is my first Hugo post
Also, let&amp;rsquo;s just try including an image because why not:</description><content>&lt;p>Hello world! This is my first Hugo post&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, let&amp;rsquo;s just try including an image because why not:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://kakan.omg.lol/cover.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://kakan.omg.lol/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</author><guid>https://kakan.omg.lol/about/</guid><description>Hi There! I go by KAKAN (He/Him)
&amp;hellip;or Hazel, based on one of my favourite characters and claimed eye colour.
I&amp;rsquo;m a student who likes playing with data, aiming to be a backend dev.
I like meeting with new people and learning new stuff!
It&amp;rsquo;s fun!
While I am studying at a university, I&amp;rsquo;m mostly self-taught. I also make game servers, for fun and experience.
I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of Facebook Meta, but I&amp;rsquo;ve quite a few socials that you can find at Contact Me page</description><content>&lt;h1 id="hi-there">Hi There!&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I go by KAKAN (&lt;em>He/Him&lt;/em>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;or Hazel, based on one of my favourite characters and claimed eye colour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a student who likes playing with data, aiming to be a backend dev.&lt;br>
I like meeting with new people and learning new stuff!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>It&amp;rsquo;s fun!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>While I am studying at a university, I&amp;rsquo;m mostly self-taught. I also make game
servers, for fun and experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of &lt;del>Facebook&lt;/del> Meta, but I&amp;rsquo;ve quite a few socials that you
can find at &lt;a href="https://kakan.omg.lol/contact-me">Contact Me&lt;/a> page&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Oh! By the way, I love Foxes!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, there&amp;rsquo;s that. Moving on to more interesting things, I&amp;rsquo;m interested in
trying out different technical solutions for web. This site is made using
&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a> and hosted using &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/">Github Pages&lt;/a>,
and for the most part, written using a text editor &lt;a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime Text 4&lt;/a>
rather than a WSYIWYG editor. Time will tell if this works out for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hope you liked this website and my introduction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See ya soon!&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Contact Me</title><link>https://kakan.omg.lol/contact-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</author><guid>https://kakan.omg.lol/contact-me/</guid><description>Socials Email: kakan@disroot.org Discord: Hazel#3811 Telegram: @theKAKAN Twitter: @ThKAKAN Other profiles I&amp;rsquo;ve one at omg.lol.
I do have a Linkedin account, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to remain pseudonymous, so I&amp;rsquo;m using a pseudonym
Like what I do?</description><content>&lt;h1 id="socials">Socials&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Email: &lt;a href="mailto:kakan@disroot.org">kakan@disroot.org&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Discord: Hazel#3811&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Telegram: &lt;a href="https://t.me/theKAKAN">@theKAKAN&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Twitter: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ThKAKAN">@ThKAKAN&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="other-profiles">Other profiles&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve one at &lt;a href="https://profile.omg.lol/kakan">omg.lol&lt;/a>.&lt;br>
I do have a Linkedin account, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to remain pseudonymous, so I&amp;rsquo;m using a pseudonym&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="like-what-i-do">Like what I do?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/kakan">
&lt;img src="https://kakan.omg.lol/images/bmc-button.svg" alt="Buy me a coffee" class="left" style="height: 3em !important; width: 10em !important;" />
&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Showcase</title><link>https://kakan.omg.lol/showcase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</author><guid>https://kakan.omg.lol/showcase/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve made some game servers, most of which are still running but are private.
The public ones, for now (could already be private by the time someone reads this):
VCMP CSGO at csgo.gboyz.xyz:27015 MTA:SA I also love to self host projects, and currently, I&amp;rsquo;m self-hosting:
Nextcloud The Lounge Jellyfin Paperless Various telegram &amp;amp; discord bots I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to try and manage public servers for Matrix and Mastodon, but I&amp;rsquo;ve not done it yet.</description><content>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve made some game servers, most of which are still running but are private.&lt;br>
The public ones, for now (&lt;em>could already be private by the time someone reads this&lt;/em>):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="vcmp://vcmp.gboyz.xyz:8192">VCMP&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CSGO at &lt;a href="csgo.gboyz.xyz:27015">csgo.gboyz.xyz:27015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MTA:SA&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I also love to self host projects, and currently, I&amp;rsquo;m self-hosting:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://nextcloud.com/">Nextcloud&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thelounge.chat/">The Lounge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://jellyfin.org/">Jellyfin&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://paperless-ng.readthedocs.io/en/latest/">Paperless&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Various telegram &amp;amp; discord bots&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to try and manage public servers for &lt;a href="https://matrix.org/">Matrix&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://joinmastodon.org/">Mastodon&lt;/a>, but I&amp;rsquo;ve not done it yet.&lt;br>
For now, only my &lt;a href="https://irc.kakan.omg.lol">The Lounge&lt;/a> is accessible to the public, along with the game servers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aside from game servers and self-hosting, I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly done analysis on publicly available datasets, so there&amp;rsquo;s not much to show here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are also a few more projects that I would like to try, but as of now, I&amp;rsquo;m doing my best to familiarise myself with the OSS world.
That includes contributing in various non-code formats, like creating issues or taking part in discussions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of that can be found in GitHub, GitLab and specific git servers related to various projects (&lt;em>like GNOME&lt;/em>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of my other stuff is available for everyone to view at either &lt;a href="https://github.com/theKAKAN">Github&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://git.kakan.omg.lol">my private Gitea server&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>