<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>selfhost on KAKAN</title><link>https://kakan.omg.lol/tags/selfhost/</link><description>Recent content in selfhost on KAKAN</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</managingEditor><webMaster>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 20:20:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kakan.omg.lol/tags/selfhost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thoughts on Indieweb</title><link>https://kakan.omg.lol/posts/thoughts-on-indieweb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 20:20:41 +0530</pubDate><author>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</author><guid>https://kakan.omg.lol/posts/thoughts-on-indieweb/</guid><description>Before we start, I&amp;rsquo;d like to point out that I&amp;rsquo;m not very well-versed on the topic, and this post is written on how/what I understand about &amp;ldquo;IndieWeb&amp;rdquo;. Do correct me if something&amp;rsquo;s wrong!
Some concepts related to the post: Webmention Think of how you can mention someone on Twitter. When you do, they get a notification for it, right? Currently, there&amp;rsquo;s no way to do that across self hosted websites ( except Mastodon, maybe?</description><content>&lt;p>Before we start, I&amp;rsquo;d like to point out that I&amp;rsquo;m not very well-versed on the topic, and this post is written on how/what I understand about &amp;ldquo;IndieWeb&amp;rdquo;. Do correct me if something&amp;rsquo;s wrong!&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="some-concepts-related-to-the-post">Some concepts related to the post:&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="webmention">Webmention&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Think of how you can mention someone on Twitter. When you do, they get a notification for it, right?
Currently, there&amp;rsquo;s no way to do that &lt;em>across&lt;/em> self hosted websites ( &lt;em>except Mastodon, maybe?&lt;/em> ).
IndieWeb and its collection of different standards tries to fix it( &lt;em>the one we are talking about right now is called Webmention&lt;/em> ). Basically, when someone links to your website from their blog, their blog( &lt;em>or some external service&lt;/em> ) posts it as a comment in your blog/wherever you want. Or when some comments on your tweet about a blog post, it&amp;rsquo;ll be cross-posted to your blog
All of that is due to &lt;strong>Webmention&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="microsubmicropub">Microsub/Micropub&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Then they have &lt;strong>Microsub/Micropub&lt;/strong>, Microsub is basically RSS but with much more features and a standard for most of them. Micropub is a standard, but for publishing instead.
The advantage here is that, you can use one app, to post to as many blogs/comment on any other blog. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to install an app( &lt;em>like Medium&lt;/em> ) to read/post/comment on their specific website. You would be able to install one app to manage everything&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="indieauth">IndieAuth&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>But, how will you prove your identity across them? That&amp;rsquo;s fixed by &lt;strong>IndieAuth&lt;/strong> using which you can define your own way of authentication, all the other websites will simply be using OAuth to connect you. This is rather neat, since you&amp;rsquo;ll be resposible for your accounts over the web.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Basically, Mastodon, right?&lt;br>
Well, yes. &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/Mastodon">Mastdon is part of the IndieWeb&lt;/a>, but it only implements some of the features, not all of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="so-why-do-i-think-its-a-privacy-nightmare">So, why do I think it&amp;rsquo;s a privacy nightmare?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The most probable reason is due to Webmention, because of which, you&amp;rsquo;ve no control where &lt;em>your&lt;/em> post/comment ends up using their &lt;em>backfeed&lt;/em>. Their wiki does discuss this: &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/backfeed#Discussion">backfeed discussion&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I think this is nice for data preservation, it&amp;rsquo;s not so nice privacy-wise or legally. It&amp;rsquo;s an action that&amp;rsquo;s much more public than people think about&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://sebastiangreger.net/2018/05/indieweb-privacy-challenge-webmentions-backfeeds-gdpr/">this excellent article&lt;/a> written by &lt;a href="https://sebastiangreger.net/">Sebastian Greger&lt;/a> that goes to great lengths to explain this and also provides some probable solution and his thoughts on the matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This article was originally written a long time ago( &lt;em>somewhere around 2019ish?&lt;/em> ) and might not be accurate anymore. Things have changed, and my understanding back then might have been wrong as well. I&amp;rsquo;ll update it sometime to reflect more of my thoughts and correct whatever mistakes there might be. Thank you.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Experience with Jellyfin</title><link>https://kakan.omg.lol/posts/jellyfin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 14:09:08 +0530</pubDate><author>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</author><guid>https://kakan.omg.lol/posts/jellyfin/</guid><description>Before we go further, I&amp;rsquo;d first like to say that I absolutely love using Jellyfin and I&amp;rsquo;ll continue using it after this, too.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the advantages!
Advantages: 1. Media metadata This is basically the reason why people would want Jellyfin over say, a file manager. It manages to grab most of my media automatically from different sites, and it&amp;rsquo;s really accurate at it too!
And if that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, it also fetches actor information, networks etc and lets you browse according to that, too.</description><content>&lt;p>Before we go further, I&amp;rsquo;d first like to say that I absolutely love using &lt;a href="https://jellyfin.org/">Jellyfin&lt;/a>
and I&amp;rsquo;ll continue using it after this, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the advantages!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="advantages">Advantages:&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="1-media-metadata">1. Media metadata&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is basically the reason why people would want Jellyfin over say, a file
manager. It manages to grab most of my media automatically from different
sites, and it&amp;rsquo;s really accurate at it too!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, it also fetches actor information, networks etc and
lets you browse according to that, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-playback-historystatistics">2. Playback History/Statistics&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Another reason I like it is because of &lt;a href="https://github.com/jellyfin/jellyfin-plugin-playbackreporting/">Playback reporting&lt;/a>
which offers a nice view of how much I&amp;rsquo;ve watched, or how many. I love seeing
data and this is really nice since it&amp;rsquo;s a centralised place for all my users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-sync-with-other-services">3. Sync with other services&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Jellyfin has plugins to sync watch lists and library with services like &lt;a href="https://github.com/jellyfin/jellyfin-plugin-trakt">Trakt.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is really nice, especially if you want to know if you already have
something in your library, or if you need to download/rip it from somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It also has your watch history, and Trakt itself provides a lot of statistics
which adds to its feature set, in my opinion.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-plugins">4. Plugins&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By default, only point 1 is possible OOTB. However, with the help of its plugin
ecosystem, you can add various things to it, like the above mentioned features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is something all of the competition has, but I still felt like I should
atleast mention it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="5-multiple-users">5. Multiple Users&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is also something that sets Jellyfin apart from &amp;ldquo;local&amp;rdquo; media managers
which let you store, view and update metadata and keep a playback history,
but tie it to a single user. Often times, its annoying and also cannot be
changed since its usually stored in NFO files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, that reminds me, Jellyfin has an option to store metadata in NFO files
at the location, which I always keep turned off because I like them
directories kept clean! :yum:&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="disadvantages">Disadvantages:&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Time to move on to the not-so-good parts in my experience of self hosting Jellyfin&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-mixed-libraries-dont-work-well">1. Mixed Libraries don&amp;rsquo;t work well&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a surprise to anybody, but if you have a lot of mixed content
i.e, TV shows and movies in one folder (&lt;em>say you have one folder for all Anime&lt;/em>),
then you should consider moving them to different folders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem arises since Jellyfin can no longer safely say &amp;ldquo;this is a movie&amp;rdquo;,
or that &amp;ldquo;this is a series&amp;rdquo;, so in the end you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with multiple movies
marked as series and vice versa. It&amp;rsquo;s mildly annoying at best, and unfixable
at worst.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>My solution&lt;/strong>: I moved Anime movies into my main Movies library, and then created
a collection of all the anime movies. That way, I can still browse them separately.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-lack-of-plugins">2. Lack of Plugins&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is mostly because Jellyfin is changing from Emby, so plugins made for Emby
might not work anymore. And because Jellyfin itself is getting updated, older
and unmaintained plugins might not work anymore either. While there are some
really good plugins that do work, it&amp;rsquo;d be nice if there were even more maintained
ones available to use&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortuneately, this is kind of a chicken egg problem and I&amp;rsquo;ve no idea how this
might get solved. That said, there are some really good plugins out there, I even
&lt;a href="https://github.com/stars/theKAKAN/lists/jellyfin-plugins">made a list of ones I found interesting&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-metadata-searchupdate-is-slow">3. Metadata Search/Update is&amp;hellip; slow&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why this happens, but if you have multiple metadata providers,
you&amp;rsquo;ll likely experience major slowdowns if you enter broad enough terms for
searching.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and sometimes the images don&amp;rsquo;t get updated. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a cache issue, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>My solution&lt;/strong>: I grab the IMDb ID and search via that, in case the builtin
metadata downloader gets/grabs the wrong metadata&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-tv-shows-are-kind-of-a-mess">4. TV Shows are kind of a mess&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Honestly, this is more of a standard/naming problem than it is with Jellyfin,
but nonetheless, it&amp;rsquo;s a problem that I experienced a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, many series are listed differently under different providers.&lt;br>
For example:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Kitsu has 6 different entries for &amp;ldquo;My Hero Academia&amp;rdquo;, for each of its different seasons.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Trakt has one entry for &amp;ldquo;My Hero Academia&amp;rdquo;, with 6 seasons inside it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This same pattern continues for many different series — as well as some movies —
which makes it annoying to efficiently categorise and manage a library.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I hope this post helped you in some way. To me, Jellyfin is not just a media
server, it&amp;rsquo;s also a playground for me to play with my collection of movies
as well as find ways to efficiently organise them for future usage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I simply chose Jellyfin as its the FOSS option, which makes it likely that
in the odd case that it gets abandoned, I might be able to keep tweaking it
to make sure that it &lt;em>just works™&lt;/em> and suits my needs.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>