<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>indieweb on KAKAN</title><link>https://kakan.omg.lol/tags/indieweb/</link><description>Recent content in indieweb on KAKAN</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</managingEditor><webMaster>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</webMaster><copyright>Copyright © 2022 KAKAN. All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 20:20:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kakan.omg.lol/tags/indieweb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thoughts on Indieweb</title><link>https://kakan.omg.lol/posts/thoughts-on-indieweb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 20:20:41 +0530</pubDate><author>kakan@disroot.org (KAKAN)</author><guid>https://kakan.omg.lol/posts/thoughts-on-indieweb/</guid><description>Before we start, I&amp;rsquo;d like to point out that I&amp;rsquo;m not very well-versed on the topic, and this post is written on how/what I understand about &amp;ldquo;IndieWeb&amp;rdquo;. Do correct me if something&amp;rsquo;s wrong!
Some concepts related to the post: Webmention Think of how you can mention someone on Twitter. When you do, they get a notification for it, right? Currently, there&amp;rsquo;s no way to do that across self hosted websites ( except Mastodon, maybe?</description><content>&lt;p>Before we start, I&amp;rsquo;d like to point out that I&amp;rsquo;m not very well-versed on the topic, and this post is written on how/what I understand about &amp;ldquo;IndieWeb&amp;rdquo;. Do correct me if something&amp;rsquo;s wrong!&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="some-concepts-related-to-the-post">Some concepts related to the post:&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="webmention">Webmention&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Think of how you can mention someone on Twitter. When you do, they get a notification for it, right?
Currently, there&amp;rsquo;s no way to do that &lt;em>across&lt;/em> self hosted websites ( &lt;em>except Mastodon, maybe?&lt;/em> ).
IndieWeb and its collection of different standards tries to fix it( &lt;em>the one we are talking about right now is called Webmention&lt;/em> ). Basically, when someone links to your website from their blog, their blog( &lt;em>or some external service&lt;/em> ) posts it as a comment in your blog/wherever you want. Or when some comments on your tweet about a blog post, it&amp;rsquo;ll be cross-posted to your blog
All of that is due to &lt;strong>Webmention&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="microsubmicropub">Microsub/Micropub&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Then they have &lt;strong>Microsub/Micropub&lt;/strong>, Microsub is basically RSS but with much more features and a standard for most of them. Micropub is a standard, but for publishing instead.
The advantage here is that, you can use one app, to post to as many blogs/comment on any other blog. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to install an app( &lt;em>like Medium&lt;/em> ) to read/post/comment on their specific website. You would be able to install one app to manage everything&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="indieauth">IndieAuth&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>But, how will you prove your identity across them? That&amp;rsquo;s fixed by &lt;strong>IndieAuth&lt;/strong> using which you can define your own way of authentication, all the other websites will simply be using OAuth to connect you. This is rather neat, since you&amp;rsquo;ll be resposible for your accounts over the web.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Basically, Mastodon, right?&lt;br>
Well, yes. &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/Mastodon">Mastdon is part of the IndieWeb&lt;/a>, but it only implements some of the features, not all of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="so-why-do-i-think-its-a-privacy-nightmare">So, why do I think it&amp;rsquo;s a privacy nightmare?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The most probable reason is due to Webmention, because of which, you&amp;rsquo;ve no control where &lt;em>your&lt;/em> post/comment ends up using their &lt;em>backfeed&lt;/em>. Their wiki does discuss this: &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/backfeed#Discussion">backfeed discussion&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I think this is nice for data preservation, it&amp;rsquo;s not so nice privacy-wise or legally. It&amp;rsquo;s an action that&amp;rsquo;s much more public than people think about&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://sebastiangreger.net/2018/05/indieweb-privacy-challenge-webmentions-backfeeds-gdpr/">this excellent article&lt;/a> written by &lt;a href="https://sebastiangreger.net/">Sebastian Greger&lt;/a> that goes to great lengths to explain this and also provides some probable solution and his thoughts on the matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This article was originally written a long time ago( &lt;em>somewhere around 2019ish?&lt;/em> ) and might not be accurate anymore. Things have changed, and my understanding back then might have been wrong as well. I&amp;rsquo;ll update it sometime to reflect more of my thoughts and correct whatever mistakes there might be. Thank you.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>